Here are some numbers that show the pattern I mentioned.
按照之前讲到的模式填好了数据
To make the pattern easier to see I've added the click-through-rate
为使模式更加简单明了
in parentheses here.
我在括号里增加了点击率
By the way, you could also have used the same numbers from the Berkeley example
你也可以使用伯克利实例里的数字
and gotten the similar pattern.
得出类似的模式
So you can see that overall the click-through-rate
可以看到 实验组整体的点击率
is lower in the experiment group than in the control group.
低于对照组
But, for both new users and experienced users,
但是实验组新用户和资深用户
the click-through-rate is higher in the experiment group.
的点击率均高于对照组
The new users also have a higher overall click-through-rate than the experienced
新用户整体的点击率高于资深用户
users, which explains why the click-through-rate
而对照组的新用户人数更多
is higher in the control group, which had more new users.
这就导致对照组的点击率较高
Now wait a minute, why are there more page views from new users in the control
不过先等一下 为什么对照组新用户的页面浏览量
group than in the experiment group?
高于实验组？
If the assignment to the control in the experiment group is random, then
如果实验组随机向对照组分配用户
shouldn't the new users be evenly split between the control and experiment?
那么两组的新用户数量不就应该持平吗？
And same for the experienced users.
而且资深用户也应该一样
The answer is they probably should be evenly split.
我的回答是 或许应该持平
Earlier, you learned it's a good idea to make sure the number of page views is
之前 你已经学过在完整性检查中
the same in the experiment group and the control group as a sanity check.
最好确保实验组和对照组的页面浏览量一致
Checking that breakdown across different slices could also be a good
检查各组的分量也可以
sanity check.
发挥完整性检查的作用
The most likely reason you would see a result like this is that something is
出现上述情况的原因很可能是
wrong with your experiment setup.
实验设置有误
However, it's also possible to get skewed numbers like this,
不过 即便设置正确
even if your setup is correct, if your change, or
如果更改措施或实验对新用户和资深用户产生不同影响
experiment, affects new users and experienced users differently.
那么也可能得到以上偏斜数据
Suppose you're diverting based on user ID and
假设根据用户 ID 分组
the change makes new users generate fewer page views, for example, they
更改措施使得新用户的页面浏览量更低 比如说 刷新页面次数减少
refresh the page less, and experienced users generate more page views.
而资深用户的浏览量却更高
That explains why there are more page views in the experiment group for
这就导致实验组资深用户和对照组新用户的
experienced users and more page views in the control group for new users.
页面浏览量更高
Now when making a recommendation for this experiment
在对实验提出建议时
it might seem tempting to say that the experiment was a success.
很容易判断说实验能够取得积极成果
After all, it was an improvement for both new users and experienced users.
毕竟新用户和资深用户的浏览量都增加了
The reason it wasn't an improvement overall is because of
但是由于在实验组和对照组之间
the fact that the new users and experienced users weren't split
新用户和资深用户的数量并未持平
evenly between the experiment and control group.
整体情况没有好转
However, you really need to dig deeper and figure out why the page views for
你得深入研究
new and experienced users are not being split evenly between the two groups.
弄清楚两组的新用户和资深用户为什么没有持平
Whether it's a faulty experiment set up, or
是因为实验设置有误
something where your change affects new and experienced users differently, you
还是更改措施对两个用户群体的影响不同
won't be able to make a valid conclusion until you understand what's going on.
只有找到原因 你才能得出有效结论